只使用压制火力
Suppression fire only.
我们这次抓活的
We take this one alive.
密集队形
Tight formation.
别告诉我 机械党居然看不出来
Don't tell me MECH never considered that
受伤的霸天虎在公开频道发出求救信号 可能是个陷阱
an open channel distress signal from an injured Decpeticon might be a trap.
下回我会牢记在心的
I'll bear that in mind next time.
下回？
Haha, next time?
你对倒霉的打击干的那些事 已经成了霸天虎无线电台的热门话题
Decepticon radio chatter's all abuzz about the workover you gave poor Breakdown.
作为一名前霸天虎成员
As an ex-Con myself
我真该收拾你一顿！
I really should have disarrayed you for that!
不过 一个故交和她的小无赖
But, an old acquaintance and her nasty little human destoried my ship and skinned my knee.
我一定要以牙还牙 干掉他们
I mean to pay them back in kind, both of them.
如你所见
You see.
我比大多数霸天虎更能适应这个鬼地方
I make it in and out of place as most Decepticons can't
但我毕竟是初来乍到
but I'm still learning to navigate this planet.
机械党能得到什么好处？
What's in it for MECH?
我会饶你一命
I'll let you live.
你本想来抢回那个受伤的“变形金刚” 对吗？
And since you came to collect that "Transformer", was it?
我可以把阿尔茜的残骸留给你
I'll throw in whatever is left of Arcee
但是 我要尝鲜
after I've broken her.
谢谢你送我回家 杰克
Thanks for walking me home, Jack.
你真有风度
You're a real gentleman.
我可不想在睡前听见你发动机的轰鸣
I don't want you reved up before bedtime.
妈妈睡觉很轻 而且…
Mom's a light sleeper, and...
我想她不会明白…
I don't think that she'd understand about...
明白什么 杰克？
Understand what, Jack?
明白这个月你为什么第三次违反宵禁？
You breaking curfew for the third time this month?
妈妈？
Mom.
明白为什么你的老板打电话 说你又没去换班？
Or why your boss called about you missing another shifted work?
还是为什么我收到 你的艺术史老师发来的邮件
Or maybe the email I received from your art-history teacher
讨论你上课时睡觉的问题？
who's concerned you've been falling asleep in class?
妈妈 他翻来覆去只说两个词 美术和历史
Well, two words, mom, art and history.
告诉我 那些传言不是真的 杰克
Tell me the rumors aren't true Jack.
告诉我 你没用摩托车去飙车
Tell me you're not racing that motorcycle.
不 不 等等…你从哪儿听说的？
No, no, wait... Where did you hear that?
这是个小地方 人言可畏
Small town, people talk.
我在急诊室工作 杰克
I work in an emergency room, Jack.
我可见过飙车的下场
I've seen what can happen.
求求你 告诉我 你没跟那群坏孩子学坏
So please, tell me you haven't fallen in with the bad crowd.
什么？
What?
不 不不 我的朋友们都是好孩子
No, no, no, no. My friends are the good crowd.
好得不能再好了
Seriously good.
我让你留下那辆车 是因为我相信 你已经够成熟了 能掌握分寸
I let you have that bike because you convinced me you are mature enough to handle it.
但我认为需要适当提醒你一下
But I think you may need a gentle reminder.
信息已查收 妈妈
Message received, mom
铭记在心
loud and clear.
这次谈话很受用
I'm glad we had this talk.
我是说
I meant
这几个星期不准骑摩托车 看你能不能收心
let's see if a few weeks without the distraction of your motorcycle will do the trick.
但是…
Eh, but...
没有但是！除了学校和工作 你哪儿也不许去
No but! You're grounded from everything but school, and work.
如果你想骑车出去
And if you want to take a bike to either
就骑自行车吧
you'll pedal.
我是认真的 杰克
Serious face, Jack.
如果我发现摩托车不在车库…
If I see that motorcycle out of the garage...
好了 去洗洗睡吧
Now, go wash up and get some sleep.
我爱你
I love you.
你被禁足期间 我会想你的
I'll miss you while you're grounded.
别担心 阿尔茜 我每天都会来看你的
Don't worry Arcee. I'll visit you here every day.
呃 杰克？
Eh, Jack?
我不能呆在这里
I won't be here.
静坐两个星期 我的轮胎肯定会胖死了
Sitting on my fat tire for two weeks is not an option.
不不不… 你也看见我妈那副表情了
No, no, no... You saw mom's serious face.
阿尔茜 让她一直蒙在鼓里 我已经感觉很愧疚了
Well, Arcee, I feel badly enough that I had to lie to her all this time
但如果你不在
but if you're not here
她会觉得 我把她的话当成耳旁风
she's gonna think that I'm blowing her off.
深呼吸 杰克
Deep breath Jack.
你妈妈很晚才下班
Your mom works late nights.
我会尽量在她到家之前 回到车库
I'll try to be back in the garage before she gets home.
但是… 不敢保证
But... no promises.
嘿 妈妈
Hey, mom.
杰克 你今晚不打算吃外卖吧
Jack, I hope you're not planning to eat take-out tonight.
我提前下班了 可以给禁足的儿子做一顿营养晚餐
I took my break early so I could cook my grounded son a wholesome dinner.
哟…有机豆腐！好东西！
Oh-organic tofu! Awesome!
嘿 你肯定比我快 我一会儿就到家
Hey, eh, car beats ten-speed. I'll be home soon.
我爱你 再见
Love you. Bye!
拜托 快接 快接 快接
Come on, pick up, pick up, pick up.
阿尔茜！你不会没在车库里吧？
Arcee! You wouldn't be in the garage right now?
我没在 杰克
Negative, Jack.
我们回头再说行吗？
Can we talk about this later?
不行 妈妈正在回家的路上
No. Mom's on her way home.
如果你不立刻回家 我就要被禁足一辈子了
If you don't race back there right now, I will be grounded for life.
而且妈妈可能让我把你拆了卖掉
And mom will make me sell you for parts.
小蜂 你能应付吗？
Bee, can you handle it?
救护车 我需要环陆桥
Ratchet, I need to bridge.
杰克！
Jack!
杰克 你居然不听我的话
Jack! I can't believe you disobeyed me.
摩托车呢？
Where is the motorcycle?
呃…
Eh...
你在说什么？
What do you mean?
我不是把她放在那儿了吗
She's right where I left her.
是你让哪个狐朋狗友偷偷送来的
Did you get one of your crew to sneak it in?
还是你刚刚推进来的？
Or did you just walk it up again?
好吧 妈妈 你真的想知道？
OK, mom. You really wanna know?
做好心理准备
Fasten your seatbelt.
我的摩托车是个有自主意识的机械生命体 来自一颗遥远的星球
My motorcycle is a sentient robotic organism from a distant planet
她的队伍驻扎在地球上
part of a team stationed here on Earth
正在打一场秘密战争
fighting a secret war.
放学后的大部分时间 我都和她的战友呆在一起
And I spent most of my time after school hanging with her crew.
杰克…
Jack...
最酷的是
And the coolest thing
这还不是她的真实形态
this isn't even her actual form.
她其实是个巨大的机器人 可以变成摩托车
She's really a giant robot, who can transform into a vehicle.
够了 杰克
Enough, Jack.
没事了 阿尔茜 现身吧
It's OK, Arcee, show yourself.
她… 她很害羞
She is... She's shy.
阿尔茜？说真的
Arcee? Really?
别再躲了 不用撒谎了
No more hiding, no more lies.
噢 拜托 出发啊！
Oh, come on, roll out already!
那么 嗯…
So, em
那群和你在一起的坏孩子是…
the bad crowd you've been hanging out with is a...
科幻俱乐部的？
science fiction club?
我要回去工作了
I have to get back to work
等我回家 我们再继续谈
we will continue this when I get home.
真是两肋插刀啊 “搭档”
Thanks for the support, "partner".
别怪我 记住…
Don't blame me, remember...
我知道 我知道…
I know, I know...
你不存在
You don't exist.
你飞船上的黑匣子 在爆炸中受到严重损毁
Your ship's black box sustained serious damage in the explosion.
但我们用软件从安保部件中 恢复了部分画面
But our software was able to reconstruct a few frames from the security thingy.
就是他
That's him.
我的杰克
My Jack.
我们的面部识别算法 会把杰克的图像发到网上
Our facial recognition algorithm will send Jack's image across the web--
不是你那种网
another kind of web.
啊… 有料了
Ah... the mother lode.
政府资料库？
Government database?
社交网站
Social networking page.
所有关于杰克的有用信息都在这里了
Everything worth knowing about Jack Darby is right here.
十六岁 内华达州贾斯帕市
Age sixteen, Jasper, Nevada.
母亲是… 琼・达比 一名护士
Mother... June Darby, a nurse.
或许我对杰克太苛刻了
Maybe I'm being too hard on Jack
可是他撒谎
but he lied.
要让他吸取教训 我只能坚持…
And the only way he's gonna learn is if I stick to my...
阿尔茜 我妈回来了吗？
Arcee, is mom home yet?
我没看见她的车
I didn't see her car.
不知道
Don't know.
我也是赶在她之前 从基地传送过来
I just bridged from base to beat her here.
哦 那儿有你的一个包裹
Oh, and there's a package for you.
你好 杰克
Hello, Jack.
塞拉斯
Silas.
这是什么？怎么回事？
What is it? What's going on?
机械党
MECH.
他们连我住哪儿都知道？
They know where I live?
我们对你家人的了解 更胜于你
We know things about your family that even you don't know.
比如 你知道你妈妈身在何处吗？
For example, do you know where your mother is?
你做了什么…
What did you...
要知道 杰克 我们不打算伤害她
Understand, Jack. We have no intention of hurting her.
事实上 我们更乐意让你们母子俩尽快团聚
In fact, we'd like to reunite the two of you as soon as possible.
只要你和阿尔茜 跟着这个通讯器内置的GPS坐标
I just need you and Arcee to follow the GPS coordinates programmed into this communicator.
它会带你们来到我的临时军营
They'll lead you to the temporary facility I've set up.
救护车…
Ratchet...
阿尔茜！
Arcee?
我是不是忘了说 我们的通讯器 能扰乱联络信号和你的大脑？
Did I not mention our communicator scrambles the signal and your brains?
无论是破解通讯 还是企图联系其他汽车人
Any break in communication or attempt to reach the other Autobots
达比小姐就会…那个…
and Miss Darby... Well
发生什么后果 我可概不负责
I wouldn't want to feel responsible for the outcome.
如果因为我被牵扯进来 导致她发生意外 我…
If anything happens to her because of my connection to all this, I...
杰克 机械党只对我感兴趣
Jack, MECH is only interested in me.
他们一旦如愿以偿
Once they get what they want
就会放了你妈妈
they'll let your mom go.
这怎么能让我安心
That's not exactly reasuring.
你也是我的家人
You're family, too.
那么… 怎么办？
So... What's the plan?
老办法
The usual.
妈妈？
Mom?
是在找琼吗？
Looking for June?
她就在附近某个地方挂着呢
She's hanging around here somewhere.
毒蜘蛛！
Airachnid!
她怎么来了？
What's she doing here?
帮帮他们 求你了
Help them, please.
他们和你一样 是人类
They are humen like you!
你不能让毒蜘蛛…
You can't let Airachnid...
几条人命不值一提 你才是我们想要的科学奇迹
A few human lives are a small price to pay for a miracle of science like yourself.
阿尔茜
Arcee...
一会儿我要和你私下里谈谈
You and I will have a private session later.
我保证
Promise.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我对人类还不完全了解
I'm still learning about human kind
但有件事我很清楚 杰克
but one thing is clear to me, Jack.
你们人类对于家人格外关心
You people care deeply about family.
因此 我能想到的最有爱心的复仇手段
Therefore, the sweetest revenge I could possibly devise
莫过于让你亲眼看我如何让你家破人亡
would be to make you watch as I take your family apart.
如果你敢伤害我妈妈
If you hurt my mother
- 我…
- I...
- 你应该记得我很喜欢赛跑
- You remember how much I enjoy sport
对吧 杰克？
don't you, Jack?
所以 我要给你个机会去救你妈妈
So I'll give you the opportunity to save your mother.
我把她藏在了这附近
I've stashed her close by.
如果你能在十二点的钟声响起前救下她
If you can rescue her before the stroke of twelve
我就把你们俩完璧归赵
I will let both of you go unharmed.
成交吗？
Deal?
如果我做不到呢？
And if I can't?
你认为呢？
What do you think?
求求你 别让她这么做
Please, don't let her do this.
你放我们走 我们谁都不说
You can let us go. We won't tell anyone.
够了
Enough.
没错 杰克
Yes, Jack.
要像个男子汉
Man up already.
六分钟
Six minutes.
妈妈 妈妈！
Mom? Mom!
虽然我们答应那个蜘蛛人 由她给你开第一刀
Now, I know we promised the spider-bot that she would have first crack at you
但是我有预感 她不再打算借刀杀人…
but something tells me she plans to turn our mutual crisscross...
而是想一箭双雕
... into a double-cross.
塞拉斯 我们现在没法把它运走
Silas, we don't have the means of transporting it right now.
那我们只能见好就收了
We'll have to cut and run.
切开她
Open her up.
妈妈！
Mom!
杰克？
Jack?
杰克 你怎么来了？
Jack, what are you doing here?
这些人是谁？
Who are these people?
我怎么跑到…这里面了？
How did I get in this, this... stuff.
别担心 妈妈 我会把你弄出来的
Don't worry, mom. I'm gonna get you out.
杰克 那些机器人都是真的吗？
Jack, the robots are real?
我提前完成了！
I beat your deadline!
恐怕没有 杰克
'fraid not, Jack.
在午夜找到你的妈妈还不算数
The task wasn't for you to find your mother by mid-night.
你必须救下她
You had to rescue her.
但时间到了
And time's up!
现在
Now.
乖乖地坐在一边
Take a seat, sit back
欣赏恐怖表演吧
and enjoy the horror show.
快点儿 先生们
Make haste, gentlemen.
弄乱一点没关系
And don't worry about making a mess.
说起来 杰克
You know, Jack.
她是你的妈妈
She is your mom.
我为什么要独享快乐呢？
Why should I have all the fun?
选择权给你 是痛苦难耐 还是痛不欲生？
So you get to choose, agonizing, or excruciating?
不 不！
No, no!
杰克 你妈妈想知道答案
Jack, your mother wants to know.
别吊她的胃口喔
Don't leave her "dangling".
你这怪物 住手！
You monster. Stop this!
时间只够取出一个部件
We only have time to take one part.
直接拿走心脏
Go straight for the heart.
让她走
Let her go.
不管谁赢谁输 残骸都是我们的
No matter the outcome, the spoils will be ours.
杰克 如果你还举棋不定
Well, Jack. If you won't decide
我想就得由女士来选择了
I guess it's lady's choice.
妈妈 对不起
Mom, I'm sorry.
不！
No!
杰克 是你的摩托车吗？
Jack, your motorcycle?
我会解释的 妈妈
I can explain, mom.
等等 我已经解释过了
Wait, I already did.
机械党放跑了打击
MECH lost Breakdown.
可他们连你都看不住吗？
What were the odds they can't hold on to you?
不！杰克！
No! Jack!
妈妈！
Mum!
杰克――！
Jaaaaack!
啊 杰克！
Ah, Jack!
坚持住 琼
Hang on, June.
瞄准那个大爬虫
Aim for the creepy crawling.
他们是怎么找到这儿的？
How did they find us?
你放我们走 我们谁都不说
You can let us go. We won't tell anyone.
多谢相救 福勒探员
Thanks for coming, Agent Fowler.
早知道还有虎子 我就该叫擎天柱来
If I'd known Con were involved, I would have called in Prime.
恐怕我妈一夜之间 受不了那么多刺激
That might have been too much for mom to handle in one night.
啊！又来这套！
Ah! Not again!
不！
No!
原来是这样的 太有才了
So that's how it's done. Genius.
达比夫人
Mrs Darby
我是特工威廉・福勒
I'm special agent William Fowler.
该让你知道真相了
It's time you knew the truth.
近几个月 杰克一直…在我处实习
For the past several months, Jack's been... interning for me at the agency.
福勒探员 我妈是不会买账的
Agent Fowler, mom's not gonna buy it.
他说对了
He's got that right.
福勒探员
Agent Fowler.
让我猜猜――什么都没留下？
Let me guess-- without a trace?
哼！
Uhh!
那么 她是你的…
And she would be your...
摩托车 保镖 汽车人 朋友
Motorcycle, guardian, Autobot, friend.
叫我阿尔茜好了
Call me Arcee.
谢谢你 阿尔茜
Thank you, Arcee.
看来我可以兑现诺言 带你去兜风了
I think it's time for that ride you once made me promise.
妈妈 这就是我的科幻俱乐部
Mom, meet my science fiction club.